# IMRAN KHAN +6016 337 8730 HUUNKHAN@GMAIL.COM



## BRAND MANAGEMENT / MARKET RESEARCH / STRATEGIC POSITIONING

Talented, results-producing Marketing Professional with a proven record of Accomplishment in planning and leading comprehensive marketing strategies in support of business goals and objectives.

Expertise in directing the creation of marketing tools and steering the Execution of marketing programs. Demonstrated success driving growth in targeted markets through implementation of key projects.

Solid leadership skills; able to build and guide top-performing marketing teams. Handle communication with management, vendors, and internal Departments to coordinate overall marketing efforts.

- Strategic Market Planning
- Marketing Collateral Development
- Brand Management
- Direct Marketing Programs
- New Market Penetration
- Market Research & Analysis
- Team Building & Management
- P/L Management

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

DIRECTOR- BUSINESS UNIT- 2011 to Date CAPTIVATE SDN BHD, DAMANSARA, PETALING JAYA, SELANGOR, Malaysia

#### **Brands Portfolio:**

Unilever, Samsung, Nestle Milo, Fonterra, Nokia, Coca-Cola, Danone Dumex, Wyeth, Ajinomoto

#### Selected Contributions:

- Create Develop and Implement the Unilever Fair concept, Organize and plan Unilever Events at all major Chains such as Gaint, Tesco, Aeon Big, Jaya Jussco, Mydin, Watson, Guardian, Caring etc
- Develop the Captivate loyalty Program for Permanent Promoters. Develop virtual web training programs, set up mobile apps so promoters get instant training and get updates
- Establish Business Intelligence Unit department to provide up-to-date sales reports, tracking reports, biz review reports, competitors analysis, SWOT analysis by campaign
- Increase Business Unit revenue from 5 Million RM to 15 Million RM per anum

# MARKETING & BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT MANAGER- 2007- 2010 MAMEE DOUBLE DECKER (M) BERHAD, SUBANG USJ, MALAYSIA

# Assign Brands:

Chilled: Nutrigen Cultured Milk, IQ3, LiteYo, Fruit Nation

Beverages- Cheers, Mamee Monster Juice, Diamond Spring Mineral Water

Snack: Mister Potato, Mamee Noodles

#### Selected Contributions:

- Drove up Nutrigen Cultured Milk sales by increase of 15% more and take over Number 3 position in terms of Volume and Value in this segment through designing and launching new marketing strategy.
- Successfully Launch IQ3 as premium brand with Unique USP (DHA, Inulin)
- Restructure LiteYo Yogurt Category Change over all marketing plans and Brand Direction. With new strategies manage to increase market share from 1.3% to 5.3% in 2007. Successfully penetrate new distribution channels.
- Leverage Mamee Monster Brand and successfully launch Monster Juice,
   Create a Healthy and Fun monster image through Monster Pouch Juice.

# MARKETING & PR MANAGER, 2003 – 2007 NESTLE – ONTARIO, CANADA

Developed and managed a wide range of marketing tools, including promotional materials, direct-mail pieces, and Web site content. Defined and evaluated product marketing collateral, programs, and analyses. Tracked, projected, and reported both advertising and circulation-based marketing programs. Maintained communication with management to ensure marketing activities aligned with business goals. Provided leadership and direction to marketing associates to guide the creation of marketing materials and ensure congruence with objectives, plan and implement

PR campaigns, work closely with PR agency to implement such campaigns.

#### Selected Contributions:

- Successfully maintained and increased client base by designing and implementing strategic customer-retention projects.
- Planned and led execution of online advertising campaign that doubled monthly revenue.
- Establish and set up new distribution channels
- Set up Nestle corners on the streets and key outlets, where consumer enjoy the ready to eat healthy products

# MARKETING AND BRAND MANAGER, 2000-2002

BIT GROUP OF COMPANIES – Stockholm, Sweden Assign Brands- Gucci, Pierre Cardin, Valentino Rudy, John Langford, Luggi Batani, Anadi,

Define strategy for and develop, execute, and manage comprehensive marketing plan encompassing integrated marketing initiatives designed to penetrate and grow targeted markets. Communicate with customers, management, internal departments, and vendors to coordinate overall marketing effort in accordance with corporate goals. Plan and carry out regional market research and analyses. Play integral role in product development activities. Lead and direct forward-thinking marketing team. Prepare and manage marketing budget.

#### Selected Contributions:

- Increase Total brands category market share by 25% through aggressive A&P campaigns, redefine the target groups and restructure the marketing plans.
- Establish and develop the Leather Accessories line for Pierre Cardin,
   Luggi Batani, Valentino Rudy and Anadi.
- Launch Pierre Cardin and Valentino Rudy Stationary Collection in Middle East cater to target Niche Market
- Set up the GUCCI outlets in Middle East and African Market.

# PROJECT OFFICER- UNICEF, 1998 - 1999

Assign Territory- Afghanistan UNITED NATION – New York, USA

Assists in providing technical guidance to Govt and NGO's counterparts to improve legal protection and justice system for children in assign country (Afghanistan), worked on children health and education programs, assists in draft papers, draft section of donor, annual and other reports.

# **SPECIAL PROJECTS**

Marketing Consultant to Monorail 2009-2010

Marketing Consultant to Chayo Sdn Bhd (F&B),

Kelana Jaya- 2009-2010 (6 months)

Marketing Consultant to Bioregen Sdn Bhd- 2011

## **EDUCATION & CREDENTIALS**

MBA, International Business Management, 2000

• Preston University, WY -USA

Term Paper- Brand Management in Globalization Era

BBA (Hon's), Marketing, 1998

• Preston University, WY - USA

BA, Fine Arts, 1997

• University of Wyoming, WY – USA

# **ADDITIONAL INFORMATION**

Nationality • Italian-Pakistan

Date of Birth • March 30th, 1978

Language Skills • Latin, English, Urdu, Thai, Arabic

## **WORK PERMIT STATUS**

Personal work permit under Talent Corp- Renewal Every Two Year